Guide to the William Graham Sumner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Although a successful teacher, Sumner did not abandon his plans to enter the ministry. On 28 December 1867 he was ordained by the Episcopal Church and three months later moved to New York City to serve as the assistant rector at the Calvary Church. One of his major accomplishments as assistant rector was to found and edit a religious journal called The Living Church. (The journal lasted barely a year, 1869-1870.) He also delivered an occasional sermon at the church and translated W.F. Bahr's Book of Kings.
During this time, the young minister found time to woo and marry Jeannie Whittemore Elliott. The two were married 17 April 1871 and had three sons, one of whom died in infancy.
After personal difficulties with the rector of Calvary Church in 1870, Sumner accepted the post of rector at the Church of the Redeemer in Morristown, New Jersey. He remained in Morristown until 1872 when the Yale Corporation appointed him to the new chair of political and social science. Sumner stayed at Yale for the rest of his career, serving as a teacher, administrator, scholar and publicist.
Sumner was undoubtedly Yale's most dynamic teacher of the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. Students clamored to enroll in his classes, and years later they continued to testify to the impact he had on their thinking. Sumner was also a champion of academic freedom and a leader in modernizing Yale's curriculum.
This devotion to academic reform nearly cost him his professorship. On 6 December 1879 Yale's President, Noah Porter, asked Sumner to ban Spencer's Study of Sociology from the classroom, arguing that it would "bring intellectual and moral harm" to impressionable undergraduates. Sumner saw this as a threat to academic freedom and bluntly refused Porter's request. The faculty soon split into two factions one supporting and the other opposing Sumner's defiance. Sumner seriously considered resigning, but friends persuaded him to stay. Eventually, his opponents capitulated and allowed Sumner to use any textbook he wanted.
Sumner's refusal to compromise and his ability to speak and write bluntly served him well outside of Yale as a publicist. From 1872 until the early 1890's Sumner wrote and spoke constantly on the economic and political issues of the day. He vigorously opposed protectionism, bimetallism, imperialism, and socialism in an acidic style which infuriated his opponents and delighted his supporters.
Sumner was a dedicated scholar as well as a nationally known polemicist. His scholarly books on economic history include: A History of American Currency (1874), Alexander Hamilton (1890), The Financier and the Finances of the Revolution (1891), and A History of Banking in the United States (1896). As an economist, however, Sumner broke no new intellectual ground. He accepted the doctrines of earlier classical economists and applied their theories to specific events.
It was as a sociologist that Sumner made his most lasting mark as a scholar. During the 1890's Sumner turned his attention to the field of sociology, or, as he later called it, the science of society. Compiling thousands of notes on the practices of various cultures, he envisioned writing a systematic work entitled Societology which he later changed to The Science of Society. After writing seventeen chapters of his book, Sumner realized his chapter on customs or "mores" was nearly a book in itself. He took time off from his main project and turned this chapter into Folkways: A Study of the Sociological Importance of Usages, Manners, Customs, Mores and Morals (1906). While never a best seller in his lifetime, Folkways became Sumner's greatest scholarly achievement, establishing him as one of America's foremost sociologists.
Following the publication of Folkways, Sumner's health, which had been poor since 1890, declined precipitously. Realizing he had neither the strength nor the energy to finish his Science of Society, he entrusted the project to his disciple, Albert Galloway Keller. Sumner never saw the finished project, which did not appear until seventeen years after his death.
Soon after his retirement in 1909, Sumner's health broke down completely. He died on 10 April 1910 in Englewood, NJ.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Separated Materials
A file cabinet containing 32 drawers of 5" x 8" notecards (approximately 250,000) used in the preparation of Science of Society was transferred to Human Relations Area Files (HRAF), in 1998.
The Living Church; Nation; Currency question; Democracy; Demonology; Economics; Education -- Connecticut; Free trade; Gold standard; Industrial organization; Marriage; Money; Prohibition; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877); Social sciences; Sociology; Students; Tariff -- United States; Witchcraft; Women; Europe; France -- Politics and government -- 1870-1940; Indiana -- Politics and government; Iowa -- Politics and government; Louisiana -- Politics and government; Southern States; Tennessee -- Politics and government; United States -- History; United States -- Politics and government -- 1865-1900; Sermons; Clergy; Educators; Sociologists; Sumner-Keller Collection; Connecticut. State Board of Education; United States. Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands; American Academy of Political and Social Science; American Social Science Association; Anti-Imperialist League; Brooklyn Revenue Reform Club; Massachusetts Tariff Reform League; New England Anti-Imperialist League; New England Free Trade League; New York Free Trade Club; Reform Club (London, England); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- History; Yale University -- Students; Yale Corporation; Yale University. Department of the Social Sciences
- Correspondence, 1854-(1863-1909)-1948; Series I; 14' (36 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Incoming Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by writer. Folders containing two or more authors indicate less significant correspondence. Many correspondents may be contained within a folder. However, only the first and last correspondents in a folder appear in the folder listings.
  Incoming Correspondence: Not to Sumner is arranged alphabetically by writer. Recipients include Sumner's children, his disciple Albert Galloway Keller, and members of families (Elliotts, Rockwells, Footes) to which Sumner was related by marriage.
  Incoming Correspondence: To Jeannie Sumner is arranged alphabetically by writer.
  Outgoing Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  W. G. Sumner to Jeannie Elliott, Sumner's outgoing correspondence to his wife before their marriage, is arranged chronologically.
  Folders with an asterisk (*) indicate ten or more letters from a single correspondent.
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Abbott, E. G. (*), 1876, 1880-1884, 1886-1889, 1891, 1893, 1895, 1898-1900, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abbot, F. E. - Charles H. Adams, 1876-1877, 1883-1884, 1889, 1897, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adams, Charles Francis, Jr. (*), 1876-1879, 1881, 1883, 1897, 1899, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, E. F. - George B. Adams, 1875, 1884, 1888-1889, 1897, 1899-1900, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Adams, Henry, 1875-1876, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      General
      See also: North American Review, box 17, folder 474
    - Adams, J. - Charles Aldrich, 1874-1875, 1878, 1880, 1883-1885, 1887, 1889-1890, 1896-1897, 1899, 1903, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Aldrich, Charles F. - Eugene Alexander, 1883-1884, 1887, 1898, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Allen, Andrew - F. F. Alling, 1869, 1872-1874, 1876-1881, 1883, 1886, 1890, 1898, 1900, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Allen, Walter
      See: box 30, folder 823-825
    - Alling, John W. - C. A. Alvord, 1870-1871, 1874, 1891, 1897-1898 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - American Academy of Political and Social Sciences - American Bell Telephone, 1880, 1883, 1885, 1889-1890, 1892, 1897-1898, 1900, 1903, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Book Company - American Rapid Telegraph Company, 1871-1872, 1875, 1880, 1882-1884, 1886-1890, 1897-1900, 1906-1908 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Social Science Association (*), 1873-1878, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      See also: box 29, folder 814-817
    - American Society for the Extension of University Teaching (*), 1895 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - American Sociological Society(*), 1907-1908, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - American Tariff Reform League - W. C. Anderson, 1875, 1878-1880, 1883, 1886, 1888-1890, 1901, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Anti-Imperialist League(*), 1898-1899, 1906-1908 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Andrews, Horace - Anthropological Society of Bombay, 1875, 1878, 1881, 1884-1886, 1888, 1896, 1898, 1900-1901, 1903, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Appleton, A. - Charles Edward Appleton, 1869-1870, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Appleton, D. and Company (*), 1884-1888, 1893, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Appleton, Henry - Charles Arms, 1869, 1875, 1877, 1886, 1889-1890, 1895, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Armstrong, A. C. and Son - Associated Press, 1878, 1881, 1886, 1898, 1900, 1904, 1908, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Atkinson, Edward - George W. Atherton, 1873, 1879, 1884, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Atterbury, Albert H. (*), 1882, 1884, 1897-1899, 1903, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Atwood, A. Watson - Howard Ayres, 1863-1864, 1879, 1881-1882, 1884, 1890-1891, 1898, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Babbitt, E. C. - Susan A. Bacon, 1870, 1872, 1876-1877, 1883, 1884, 1887, 1891, 1898, 1901, 1904, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Badger, Richard - Balch Brothers, 1872, 1879, 1887, 1889-1891, 1895, 1894, 1901, 1905, 1907, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Baldwin, Charles S. - P. C. Barker, 1875-1876, 1879, 1880-1882, 1885, 1887-1891, 1895-1897, 1900, n.d (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Baldwin, Simeon E.
      See: box 19, folder 520
    - Barnard, J. M. - William Bartlett, 1875-1876, 1878, 1880-1883, 1885, 1887, 1890, 1901, 1903-1904, 1908, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bastable, C. Francis - Thomas Bayne, 1869, 1874, 1877, 1883-1884, 1886-1890, 1898-1900, 1906, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Beach, Edward - R. G. Beach, 1876, 1879, 1908, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Beadle, Elias R. (*), 1863-1866, 1869, 1872, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Beadle, Heber H. (*), 1864-1865, 1879, 1882-1883, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Beadle, Henry M., 1876 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Beall, J. A. - J. D. Beckwith, 1867, 1874, 1876, 1882, 1884-1890, 1894, 1896-1897, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Beecher, Henry Ward
      See: box 3, folder 60
    - Bedell, Bradbury - Henry A. Beers, 1869, 1881, 1883-1884, 1886, 1895, 1899, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Beers, Henry
    - Belden, William - George Bendelari, 1869-1870, 1875, 1878, 1884-1886, 1888-1890, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Benedict and Company - M. H. Betts, 1873-1874, 1876, 1881-1882, 1885, 1895, 1897, 1903-1904, 1908, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Betts, Frederic (*), 1873, 1875-1877, 1884, 1887, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Bickford, F. S. - F. G. Bigelow, 1869, 1889, 1897, 1899, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Bigelow, John (*), 1876(?), 1886, 1889 1900-1901, 1908, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Bigelow, Poultney, 1880-1881, 1883-1884, 1886, 1908, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
      See also: box 17, folder 467
    - Bigelow, Russell - James Bixler, 1876, 1878-1879, 1881, 1884-1885, 1887-1888, 1896-1897, 1899, 1904, 1906-1907, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Blake, E. C. - Charles Blumley, 1869, 1872, 1875, 1879-1880, 1884, 1886-1887, 1889, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Boals, J. C. - Thomas K. Boltwood, 1865, 1868-1872, 1888, 1890-1892, 1896, 1899-1901, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - The Bond Record - Edward P. Boon, 1878, 1880, 1882-1884, 1889, 1903, 1906, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Booth, Edw. (*), 1876-1877 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Booth, E. M. - Allan Bourn, 1863, 1875-1878, 1886, 1895, 1898, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Bourne, Edward G. (*), 1883-1893 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Bouton, J. W., 1903 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Bowen, Clarence W. (*), 1878-1881, 1888-1889, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Bowen, Henry C., 1880, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Bowen, John Eliot (*), 1883, 1886-1888 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bowers, Arthur - Edward Bowers, 1877, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Bowker, R. R. (*), 1876-1880, 1883-1886,1889 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      See also: American Free Trade League, box 1, folder 11
    - Bowles, Leonard C. - G. M. Boyle, 1869, 1875, 1884-1886, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Brackett, Anna C. - Oliver E. Branch, 1872-1877, 1879-1883, 1885-1889, 1899, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Branford, V. - Mary Bridgman, 1869-1870, 1872, 1874, 1877, 1880, 1884-1887, 1899, 1901, 1904, 1908, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Bridgman, Raymond L. (*), 1875, 1877, 1883, 1885-1886, 1899-1900 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Brien, T. T. - Arthur W. Brody, 1864, 1870, 1876-1877, 1879, 1881, 1885-1887, 1889-1891, 1897, 1900, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Brody, Arthur W.
      See: box 5, folder 107
    - Brooklyn Revenue Reform Club (*), 1881, 1883-1886 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Brooklyn Single Tax Club - Mary Brooks, 1870, 1878, 1881, 1883, 1886-1887, 1889, 1890, 1895-1897, 1899, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Brooks, Phillip - Brown University Historical and Economic Association, 1869-1870, 1876, 1879, 1886, 1889-1890, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Brown, Edward F. (*), 1883, 1885-1887, 1889, 1901, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Brown, F. W. - James Brown, 1865, 1876, 1880-1881, 1884, 1886, 1888, 1897-1898, 1900-1901, 1903, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Brown, John Mason - T. T. Bryce, 1874-1875, 1877, 1880, 1882-1885, 1888, 1891, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Buchanan, John L. - J. A. Buckley, 1873-1874, 1878-1879, 1884, 1887-1889, 1896-1897, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Bucklin, George A., Jr. - Walter H. Burns, 1873-1876, 1882-1884, 1887, 1890, 1906, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Burr, Kate S. - T. E. Burton, 1878, 1882, 1884, 1887, 1899-1901, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Bush, Celeste E. (*), 1883-1884, 1899, 1901, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Bush, Sarah J. - Harold E. Buttrick, 1872, 1874, 1876, 1881, 1883, 1886-1887, 1889-1890, 1892, 1895, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Cadwalader, John J. - J. Caller, 1878, 1882-1883, 1885, 1887, 1889, 1896, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Calmont, E. S. - S. S. Camp, 1869, 1875, 1878, 1880, 1885, 1887-1888, 1901, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Camp, Walter C. (*), 1895, 1897, 1901, 1903-1904, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Camp, Mrs. Walter
      See: box 22, folder 622-627
    - Campbell, Archibald, 1865-1866 (Box 3, Folder 74-75)
    - Campbell, Archibald (*), 1867-1872 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Campbell, Archibald, 1873-1875 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Campbell, Archibald (*), 1876-1883 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Campbell, Archibald (*), 1884-1886, 1888-1907 (Box 4, Folder 79-83)
    - Campbell, Archibald, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Campbell, L. J. - Charles Carleton, 1873, 1876, 1883, 1887-1888, 1891, 1897-1901, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Carleton, J. N. - D. Y. Carpenter, 1875, 1882-1884, 1887, 1890, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Carrington, George M. - Charles H. Carroll, 1867, 1879, 1885-1888, 1890, 1897, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Carter, Franklin, 1875, 1880, undated (Box 4, Folder 88)
      See also: box 19, folder 520
    - Carter, Leslie - Century Company, 1872, 1878, 1881-1882, 1885-1886, 1889-1890, 1892-1893, 1897, 1899-1900, 1908, undated (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Century Club (Box 4, Folder 89)
      See also: box 2, folder 40
    - Chadwick, F. E. - Z. Chafee, Jr., 1881, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Chailley, Joseph (*), 1887, 1889-1890, 1893, undated (Box 4, Folder 91)
      See also: box 20, folder 534
    - Chalmers, Andrew Burns - Daniel Chamberlain, 1873, 1875, 1877-1878, 1887, 1899-1901, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Chamberlain, Frank - L. B. Chandie, 1867-1869, 1874-1875, 1877, 1883-1888, 1890, undated (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Channing, F. A. - S. H. Chapman, 1885, 1887, 1898, 1901, undated (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Charities - W. S. Charmley, 1882, 1884, 1886, 1898-1899, 1907-1908 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Chase and Company - Mary S. Choate, 1872, 1877-1879, 1881, 1883, 1887, 1901, 1904, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Christern, F. W. (*), 1871-1874, 1876, 1886-1887, 1889, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Christian World Publishing Co. - A. Churchill, 1870-1871, 1874, 1876-1877, 1883-1884, 1886-1887, 1896, undated (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - City and State Publishing Company - Civil Service Association, 1885, 1899-1900, 1903-1904, 1906-1908 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Claflin, Fred A. - C. H. Clark, 1870-1871, 1883-1884, 1893, 1896-1897, 1901, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Clark, Charles Hopkins (*), 1874-1875, 1881-1882, 1885, 1897, 1899, undated (Box 5, Folder 101)
      See also: box 11, folder 295-305
    - Clark, Daniel - Martin Clark, 1870, 1876, 1885-1886, 1888-1890, 1893, 1898, 1901, 1903, undated (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Clark, S. A. - W. S. Clark, 1869, 1878, 1880, 1880, 1888-1890, 1907, undated (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Clarke, James W. - Robert Clarke Company, 1869, 1876, 1881, 1883, 1890, 1894, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Clay, Cassius M., 1878, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Clement, E. H. - John Cobb, 1873, 1878, 1882-1884, 1889, 1891, 1893, 1899-1901, 1903, undated (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Cobden Club (*), 1873, 1876, 1880-1881, 1883, 1885-1886, 1889-1890, 1893, 1904, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Coe, E. B. - J. L. Cole, 1868, 1870-1871, 1876-1878, 1881, 1883-1884, 1886, 1898, undated (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Cole, John M. - Colorado Summer School, 1876, 1878-1879, 1881, 1883, 1885, 1889-1890, 1893, 1895, 1897, 1903, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Collier, Peter
      See: box 12, folder 327-329
    - Colton, Asa S. - R. W. Conant, 1869, 1872, 1874, 1880, 1897, 1908, undated (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Conant, S. S. (*), 1882-1884 (Box 5, Folder 111)
      See also: Harper's Weekly, box 10, folder 282
    - Condit, C. L. - Connecticut Sunday School Association, 1867, 1874, 1876, 1878-1879, 1883, 1886, 1890-1891, 1897, 1899-1900, 1903, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Connecticut Tariff Reform League, 1885-1887 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Connecticut Valley Economic Association - John W. Converse, 1882, 1888, 1894, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Conway, Dr. Monroe Daniel, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Cook, Albert S. - Thomas Cook, 1878-1879, 1881, 1883 1889-1890, 1908, undated (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Cooke, John W. (*), 1864-1867, 1871, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Cooke, L.A., - Luigi Copa, 1880-1883, 1886-1890, 1898, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Cooley, E. G.
    - Corbett, J. W. - R. W. Covington, 1877-1880, 1882-1883, 1887, 1890-1891, 1897, 1903, undated (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Cowles, James Lewis (*), 1879-1880, 1884-1888, 1899, 1901, 1907, undated (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Cowles, Will H. - Jesse Cox, Jr., 1875, undated (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Coxe, M. - The Critic, 1869, 1877, 1882, 1897, 1899, 1907, undated (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Crocker, Uriel Haskell(*), 1884 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Croffat, W. A. - Neander N. Cronholm, 1876, 1900, undated (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Crossley, James J. (*), 1898-1900, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Crouch, M. C. - Alexander Cumming, 1863, 1876, 1896, 1898, 1901, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Cumming, George, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 127)
      See also: box 5, folder 111
    - Cummins, A. W. - William E. Cushing, 1869, 1873, 1876, 1879-1880, 1883, 1886, 1888, 1893, 1897, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Cutler, H. G. - Cyclostyle Company, 1884, 1889, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Daboll, H. E. - Caroline B. Dana, 1876, 1883-1884, 1898, 1900-1901, 1903-1904, 1906, 1908-1909, undated (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Dana, E. S. (*), 1884-1907, undated (Box 6, Folder 131-132)
    - Dana, Harry A. - Bowie Dash, 1875-1876, 1879, 1889-1890, 1895, undated (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Dass, B. K. - N. E. Dawson, 1872, 1874, 1881, 1886, 1888, 1890, 1894, 1897-1898, 1900, 1906-1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Day, Clarence, 1903, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Day, Clive, 1897-1898 (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Day, Edward M. - H.S. De Forest, 1869-1871, 1874, 1876, 1880-1882, 1898-1899, 1903, undated (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - De Forest, Robert (*), 1872-1874, 1876-1877, 1879, 1885, 1897, 1903, undated (Box 6, Folder 138-139)
    - DeHeart, John S. - Clarence Deming, 1873-1874, 1877, 1879-1880, 1885, 1887, undated (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - DeKay, Charles (*), 1877-1885, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Democratic Club of East Orange, New Jersey - Chauncey Depew, 1876-1877, 1885, 1895, 1897, 1900, 1904, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Derby, George - Melvil Dewey, 1867, 1869-1870, 1877, 1881-1882, 1896, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Dexter, Franklin B. (*), 1871-1872, 1874, 1880, 1890-1891, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Dexter, Franklin B. - J. W. Diller, 1868-1869, 1877, 1883, 1885, 1899, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Dimock, Henry F. (*), 1865-1866, 1878, 1883, 1891, 1893-1895, 1899, 1903, 1906, 1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Dimock, Susan (*), undated (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Dimock, W. - George B. Dixwell, 1876-1877, 1882, 1887, undated (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Dodd, Mead and Company, 1889-1893, 1899, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Dodd, Dan - Julia E. Dodge, 1871-1872, 1881-1882, 1886-1887, 1899-1900, undated (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Dodge, J. Smith (*), 1871-1887 (Box 6, Folder 151-152)
    - Dodge, J. Smith, Jr. (*), 1877, 1881, 1887, 1893, 1896, 1899-1900, undated (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Dodge, S. D. - W. E. Dodge, 1873, 1885, 1888 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Dodsworth, John W. - M. J. Dodsworth, 1895, 1896, 1901, 1906, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Dodsworth, W. (*), 1885, 1895-1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Doer, F. - Domestic Missions, 1871, 1901, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Dondlinger, P., 1904, 1906-1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Donnat, L. - George P. Douglas, 1869, 1875-1876, 1878, 1881, 1884-1885, 1887-1888, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Douglas, George William (*), 1894-1898 (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Dowd, Willis B. - I. Dudley, 1875-1876, 1880-1882, 1904, 1906, undated (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Dudley, T. U., 1867, 1885 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Duffield, Samuel - Edward Dunham, 1872, 1879-1882, 1885 1888, 1903, 1908, undated (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Dugdale, R. L.
      See: Society for Political Education, box 22, folder 602
    - Dunham, Mary (*), undated (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Dunham, Theodore - Henry Dutton, 1867, 1872, 1874-1875, 1889, 1893, 1897, 1901, 1907, undated (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Dutton, S. T. - G. Dwight, 1872, 1882-1885, undated (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Dwight, Timothy (*), 1872-1887 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Dwight, Timothy (*), 1889-1896, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Drysen and Pfeiffer - G. B. Eager, 1893, 1897, 1901, 1904 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Drysen and Pfeiffer
      See also: box 4, folder 97
    - Earle, Abraham L. (*), 1873-1878, 1882 (Box 7, Folder 170-172)
    - Earle, Abraham (*), 1883-1884, undated (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Earle, William B. - N. L. Eastman, 1876, 1879, 1883, 1901, 1907, undated (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Easton, Morton W., 1866, 1869-1872, undated (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Easton, Morton W. (*), 1873-1880, 1885, 1888, 1893, 1895, undated (Box 7, Folder 176-179)
    - Easton, W. - William Eaton, 1873-1874, 1876, 1879-1880, 1884, 1886, 1898, 1903, undated (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Eckles, A. J. - H. Eede, 1882-1883, 1886, 1888, 1899, 1904, 1906-1908 (Box 7, Folder 181)